<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dynamic Programming | Диана</title>
    <link>/tags/dynamic-programming/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/dynamic-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Dynamic Programming</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>/tags/dynamic-programming/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markov Chains in Finance</title>
      <link>/project/internal-project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/internal-project-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, the binomial and trinomial asset pricing models were investigated. The calibration of the model parameters was done by different methods, in particular Cox-Ross-Rubinstein, Jarrow-Rudd, Desmond John Higham. One application of these models is the evaluation of options and obligations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several methods exist to price options and one of them is Monte-Carlo Markov Chain method (MCMC), typically used for pricing path-dependent options. Monte-Carlo Markov chain algorithm is used to simulate from complex statistical distributions by way of a local exploration of these distributions. This local feature avoids heavy requests on understanding the nature of the target, but it also potentially induces a lengthy exploration of this target, with a requirement on the number of simulations that grows with the dimension of the problem and with the complexity of the data behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why we also investigate another method to price the option that is implemented by Dynamic Programming, which is iterative and more rapid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beside that the greeks (Delta, Gamma, Vega) for some options were investigated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project was implemented in Matlab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
